# Amr Ahmed Ali

aamr9465@gmail.com

Contact Address: Haram, Jizah, Egypt Phone: 01115772391

**Military Status** 

Exempted

**About** 

I'm android developer since 2017, worked in many software companies with

different types of experience,

I have the ability to create projects starting from design up to implementation and testing with different android components and

frameworks.

Work experience

**Eva Pharma** 

Dec 2021 - Present

Senior Android Engineer

Developed many medical apps such as limitless Care App for Limitless Care medical assurance company for helping its clients to do some operations like Booking doctor appointment, check their medical network and book test labs.

Also, SPOC apps which help medical reps agents in making their plans and help medical reps managers in approving or rejecting those plans.

**IDEMIA EGYPT** 

Oct 2019 - Nov 2021

Android Developer

Achieved many national service projects using SDK which detects user identity remotely dependent on his biometrics besides other android framework components with Java and SVN VCS

YOUXEL Technology

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019

Android Developer

Achieved "My store" e-commerce app for KSA market.

**Crystal Mind** 

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

Software Developer

# Vodafone International Service

Android Developer

Participated in developing new User Stories and fixing issues at different existing VIS components such as Net Perform, Commonui and Biometrics using Java and Git VCS

### **Skills**

- Jetpack Compose
- Coroutines, RX Java and Multithreading
- Dagger and Hilt
- MVI, MVVM and MVP design Patterns
- Flow and Livedata
- Retrofit, JSON, and Networking
- Room and SQLite
- Data store and Shared Preferences
- jetpack ViewModel
- Picasso and Glide
- Activities, Fragments, Intents, Services, Broadcast Receiver and Content Providers
- OOP & SOLID principles
- Clean code & clean Architecture
- Unit Test
- Firebase Services

### **GP Project:**

Abnormal Behavior Detection with Very Good grade

### Language:

Arabic: Native

English: reading and writing (Very Good)

#### **Personal Skills:**

Team worker, managestress, supporting others, sociable.

Excellent leadership skills, can deal with all kinds of people.

Excellent time management and communication skills.

Ability to manage multiple tasks.

Interactive and fast to learn new technologies and sciences.

### **Education**

### **BS of Computer Science**

Helwan University

CS Department batch 2017 GPA 2.31

## **Qualifications**

Android, Java, Kotlin, Python, PHP, C++, C

Web Design: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, AngularJS

Database: SQL Server, MySQL

Logic programming: Prolog

## **Scholarships**

- 3-month One Million Arab Coder Scholarship Android basics
- 3-week ITI Scholarship Android Development
- 3-month Google Scholarship Advanced Android Development

### Links

### **Limitless Care App:**

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evaph.se7etak

### **SPOC Agent:**

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evaph.spoc\_agent

### **SPOC Manager:**

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evaph.spoc\_manager

### GitHub:

https://github.com/AmrAhmed2017

### LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amr-ahmed-3b1169166/